<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="design_document.xsl"?>

<design_document>
	
	<information>
		<title>Boomtown</title>
		<graphic>./facebook/styles/boomtown/images/main_header.jpg</graphic>
		<modified>0.2 - April 26th, 2011</modified>
		<changes>
			<change type="addition">Added version and date</change>
			<change type="subtraction">Removed 'tasks' section</change>
			<change type="subtraction">Removed 'Bridge' feature</change>
			<change type="subtraction">Removed 'War Room' feature</change>
			<change type="subtraction">Removed 'Factory' feature</change>
			<change type="addition">Added 'Setting' feature</change>
			<change type="addition">Added optional 'background' section</change>
			<change>Updated 'Commander' feature</change>
			<change>Updated 'Faction' feature</change>
		</changes>
		
		<description>
			BoomTown is an online, social strategy game where players assume control of a Mobile Command Center and a standing army and wage war against other factions.
		</description>		
	</information>
	
	<feature>	
		<title>Setting</title>
		<id>setting</id>
		
		<contact>		
			<author>David Talley</author>
			<email>dtalley@gmail.com</email>
			<related_sections>
				<section>faction</section>
				<section>kovanite</section>
			</related_sections>		
		</contact>
		
		<goals>		
			<goal>Provide an immersive back story and environment for the player to engross themselves in.</goal>
			<goal>Provide a reason for the player to play the game and achieve in-game goals.</goal>
		</goals>
		
		<background>
			The year is 2106.  Humankind sent probes into deep, unexplored space, only to find it absent interesting or useful planets, with the exception of Kova, a planet devoid of life, but rich in consumable resources.  Kovanite, a mineral not found on Earth, proved to be invaluable in the manufacture of mankind’s most advanced technology, and many large companies rushed equipment and manpower to the planet in order to extract it.  The natural deposits ran out, causing companies to establish mining facilities, which naturally became points of conflict.  Almost a century later, three organizations control most of the planet, and wage an all out war against each other to claim the richest mineral deposits, intent on mining valuable resources from beneath the planet’s surface and utilizing them for their own ends.<br /><br />
			
			Players take on the role of a military commander, in command of an immense battle station and a small army within, tasked by their chosen organization to secure Kovanite and transport it back to headquarters, and hinder enemy corporations from doing so wherever possible.
		</background>
		
		<implementation>		
			From the moment players launch the game, even if they aren't logged in, the game's setting should permeate the experience.  They should feel as though they have suddenly become part of this world, as though their presence on Kova is immediately requested.  An unregistered player should be plasterd with "Visit Kova" propoganda from the different factions, enticing them to "join the fight for Kovanite."
		</implementation>
		
		<impact>
			The player will always need a fictional reason, however unlikely or boring, to perform their actions in the game.  Some players need more immersion than others, and since Boomtown is a two-dimensional game with limited graphics power behind it, the story and setting behind the game needs to be relatively substantial.  A well thought out setting will give the player motivation behind their actions within the game, and a reason to continue hoping for their faction's success.
		</impact>
	</feature>
	
	<feature>	
		<title>Commander</title>
		<id>commander</id>
		
		<contact>		
			<author>David Talley</author>
			<email>dtalley@gmail.com</email>
			<related_sections>
				<section>mobile_command_center</section>
				<section>faction</section>
				<section>soldier</section>
			</related_sections>		
		</contact>
		
		<goals>		
			<goal>Provide an overarching role that the player can assume.</goal>
			<goal>Provide an embodiment for the player within the game.</goal>
			<goal>Provide a means to represent one player to another player in a recognizable form.</goal>		
		</goals>
		
		<background>
			Due to massive population growth on Earth, many able young men and women venture to Kova to fight for one of the controlling organizations with the promise of money and power.  With the advent of clone soldiers and remote battlefield control, commanding an army on Kova is relatively safe, providing a very effective lure for the organizations needing substantial manpower to secure their place on the planet.
		</background>
		
		<implementation>		
			The commander is the representation of the player within the game.  The player creates a "commander card" when they first sign up, providing a standard, recongizable way to represent their individualism to themselves and other players.  The commander card includes a photo provided by the player, as well as a visible rank insignia so other players viewing the commander card can instantly tell what rank the commander is.  The commander controls a single mobile command center at a time, and a commander fights for a single faction.		
		</implementation>

		<impact>		
			All actions the player wants to take will be 'carried out' by their commander.  This serves to separate the player from their counterpart in the game, just in case future versions include the ability to use more than one commander.  The commander also helps other players identify the player, because each commander will be unique in name and appearance (both of which are provided by the player).		
		</impact>
	</feature>
	
	<feature>
		<title>Faction</title>
		<id>faction</id>

		<contact>
			<author>David Talley</author>
			<email>dtalley@gmail.com</email>
			<related_sections>
				<section>commander</section>
				<section>world_map</section>
				<section>mobile_command_center</section>
				<section>resource</section>
				<section>equipment</section>
				<section>kovanite</section>
			</related_sections>
		</contact>

		<goals>
			<goal>Provide a 'side' for the Player to fight for.</goal>
			<goal>Allow friends to join the same team and play towards the same goals.</goal>
			<goal>Allow anyone to distinguish easily between the different sides based on color, pattern, logo silhouette, or any combination.</goal>
		</goals>

		<background>
			The three (3) factions within the game are:<br /><br />
			
			<strong>The Interplanetary Kova Company</strong> <em>(IKC)</em><br />
			A defense powerhouse, responsible for a substantial part of Earth's arms trade.  War is an eventuality on Earth, and the need for weapons never waivered.  The IKC is fighting to secure a steady supply of Kovanite to its factories on Earth to support the armies of the future.  The IKC is responsible for designing most of the weaponry used by commanders of all factions on Kova.<br /><br />
			
			<strong>Ekova, Inc.</strong> <em>(EKV)</em><br />
			A family-owned industrialist corporation responsible for many of Earth's environmentally friendly advances.  Ekova handles many of Earth's major metropolitan infrastructure contracts, building roads, apartments, parks, and many other civil installations.  Ekova uses Kovanite in many of its projects, and has a vested interest in its continued export from Kova to Earth, preferrably via its own transport ships to internal storage facilities.  Ekova is responsible for designing most of the vehicles used by commanders on Kova, including the standard mobile command centers.<br /><br />
			
			<strong>Kovanant</strong> <em>(KVN)</em><br />
			A rogue, technology-obsessed umbrella corporation fighting to take absolute control over Kova and turn it into a space-faring utopia.  Many of its subsidiaries on Earth are simply buffer companies used to filter money around the planet and especially offworld to support its military engagements on Kova itself.  Kovanant is responsible for much of the auxiliary equipment and body augmentations used by soldiers on Kova.
		</background>

		<implementation>
			There are three (3) factions within the game, and upon signing up the player must choose one to join.  The decision is permanent, so the player cannot switch factions later on.  On the faction select screen, it should be readily apparent whether or not they have friends playing for a specific faction, or all 3 if that happens to be the case.  The player should also be able to see specifically which of their friends is on which faction.<br /><br />
			
			Each faction is distinguished by a color, a pattern, and a logo, where each color is easily discernable from the next, more than likely Red, Blue, and Yellow for the most accessibility.  Each logo should also be easily recognizable by its silhouette alone.  When a faction's color is painted anywhere, it should be painted in that faction's pattern, for example dashed lines, curvy lines, circles, etc.  Each pattern should also be easily distinguishable.<br /><br />
			
			Within the game, the player should also be able to donate specific equipment and resources to their faction.  There should be specific restrictions on what the player can and cannot give, but the player should know that if they give specific things to their faction headquarters they will be rewarded.  Specifically, the player should always be able to give Kovanite to their faction headquarters, and there could be a meter that gradually fills up as the many players fighting for the faction donate to it, and once it is full, all players of that faction receive something.<br /><br />
			
			Each player should also have a news feed on their world map that pulls in broadcasts from their faction headquarters, giving them small tidbits of story development about their faction.
		</implementation>
		
		<impact>
			Factions provide animosity for players, meaning a player from one faction wants to defeat players from other factions, so it gives all players on one faction a unified goal: to promote and progress their faction while hindering enemy factions.  A faction should also provide benefits to its players, depending on the throughput of Kovanite or other resources and equipment, meaning if players substantially contribute to their faction's success, either by winning battles and securing territories, or sending sufficient Kovanite back to faction headquarters, the players should receive perks relative to their actions, such as attack bonuses, equipment, or any temporary improvements to any of the actions they may perform in the game.
		</impact>
		
	</feature>

	<feature>
		<title>Mobile Command Center</title>
		<id>mobile_command_center</id>

		<contact>
			<author>David Talley</author>
			<email>dtalley@gmail.com</email>
			<related_sections>
				<section>commander</section>
				<section>soldier</section>
				<section>equipment</section>
				<section>vehicle</section>
				<section>resource</section>
			</related_sections>
		</contact>

		<goals>			
			<goal>Provide a representation in game for the Player's location.</goal>
		</goals>

		<implementation>
			A Mobile Command Center (MCC) can either be 'Flying' or 'Rolling', which is to say one flies through the air and one rolls over the ground.  The Player chooses which MCC they would like to control when they first sign up.  The MCC is also what holds all of the Player's Soldiers, Equipment, Vehicles, and Resources.
		</implementation>
		
		<impact>
			The Mobile Command Center (MCC) provides the Player with a base of operations.  It has a bridge where they can access all of the different rooms of the MCC and perform all of the actions available to them.  The MCC also provides a physical manifestation of the player on the World Map.  The MCC serves as the central hub of almost all of the game actions, which means a lot of the Player's time is spent within the MCC managing their assets.
		</impact>		
	</feature>
	
	<feature>
		<title>World Map</title>
		<id>world_map</id>

		<contact>
			<author>David Talley</author>
			<email>dtalley@gmail.com</email>
			<related_sections>
				<section>faction</section>
				<section>mobile_command_center</section>
				<section>territories</section>
				<section>zones</section>
				<section>scenarios</section>
			</related_sections>
		</contact>

		<goals>
			<goal>Provide a global scale for the game.</goal>
			<goal>Allow the player to easily see the entire game map, and the major events taking place within it.</goal>
		</goals>
		
		<background>
			Kova is made up of a single major landmass, with many small outlying islands, but the major concentration of valuable resources lies in the center of the continent.  The landscape is Earth-like, with rolling hills, mountains, valleys, forests, and plains, but only flora and minor, unintelligent fauna live on the planet's surface.  
		</background>

		<implementation>
			The world map is where the player manages the locations of all of their actions.  They can see a full view off all of the territories in the game, which ones are disputed, which ones their faction is defending, and which ones their faction is attacking.  Each of the territories is color coded, depending on which faction currently holds the territory.  Some territories may not be occupied, in which case their color will not reflect any of the factions.<br /><br />
			
			The player can click each territory and view a popup menu that reveals information about the territory, specifically:
			<ul>
				<li>Whether or not it is disputed</li>
				<li>The number of battles occuring within it</li>
				<li>The number of friendly command centers stationed within it</li>
				<li>The number of enemy command centers stationed within it</li>
				<li>An icon allowing them to zoom into the territory to view its zones</li>
				<li>An indicator of the richness of resources within the territory</li>
			</ul>
			
			The overlay of the world map should include most of the information vital to the player's gameplay, including:
			<ul>
				<li>The number of faction dropship credits the player has left</li>
				<li>The used and unused bandwidth of the player's command center</li>
				<li>The current balance of their credit account</li>
				<li>A listing of friends</li>
			</ul>
		</implementation>
		
		<impact>
			The World Map is the center of the global conflict in the game.  It allows the player to easily see where the action is, and allows them to easily jump into it.  The World Map also serves as the initial entry point for the game.  It is the first screen the player sees when logging in, and links through to all of the major actions the player can perform within the game.
		</impact>
	</feature>
	
</design_document>